Guide to the Albert Ellis papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Albert Ellis Papers,
1920-2007
[Bulk Dates: 1965-1997].
Ellis, Albert, 1913-2007.
218 linear ft. (215 record cartons, 1 document box 6 oversize document boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library New York, NY. 10027
MS#1550
8683406
This collection encompasses the professional and personal life of psychologist and pioneer of Rational Emotive Behavior Therapy Albert Ellis.
Biographical Note
Albert Ellis was born in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, on September 27, 1913 to Hettie and Henry Oscar Ellis. He was the eldest son, with a brother, Paul, and sister Janet. Not long after Ellis was born, his family moved to New York City, where he was raised. When Ellis was 12 years old, his parents divorced. As a child, he also suffered from kidney disorder. He became a voracious reader, focusing on philosophy, and used many of these philosophic teachings to train himself to tackle his shyness and overall anxiety about a variety of undertakings in life.
Ellis wanted to be a writer, more specifically a novelist. Between the ages of 19-28, he sent multiple book-length manuscripts out for publication. After continuous rejection, he decided to attempt non-fiction instead. He began to write about sex and many of his friends and family sought his advice. He enjoyed counseling and decided to become a professional therapist. He obtained his bachelor’s degree in business administration from the City College of New York in 1934, and M.A. (1943), and Ph.D. degrees in clinical psychology from Columbia University in 1947.
During the 1940s, Ellis taught at Rutgers and New York University. He also acted as senior clinical psychologist at the New Jersey Mental Hygiene Clinic, served as Chief Psychologist of the New Jersey State Diagnostic Center and at the New Jersey Department of Institutions and Agencies. In addition, he acted as consultant in clinical psychology to the New York City Board of Education and to the Veterans Administration.
Ellis originated Rational Emotive Behavior Therapy (REBT) in 1955 as a cognitive behavioral system of psychotherapy. REBT teaches clients to use cognitive, emotive, and behavioral methods to counter their self-sabotaging beliefs and behaviors. During the 1960s and 1970s, similar forms of Cognitive Behavior Therapy (CBT) were developed, many of which drew on REBT.
In 1957, Ellis published his first book on REBT, How to Live with a Neurotic. He went on to publish 54 books and hundreds of articles. He founded and organized the Institute for Rational Living (Albert Ellis Institute) in 1959, in Manhattan where it is still operating presently. He gave Friday Night Workshops, which demonstrated REBT methodology in a public forum, at the Institute for over 30 years. Ellis served as President Emeritus of the Institute until his death on July 24, 2007. Ellis is survived by his wife, Dr. Debbie Joffe Ellis, who continues his legacy by advocating for REBT through presentations, articles, and counseling.
Ellis served as President and fellow of the American Psychological Association, Division of Consulting Psychology. He was a president, of the Society for the Scientific Study of Sex, and was a fellow of the American Orthopsychiatric Association, the American Sociological Association, the American Association of Marriage and Family Therapists, the American Association for the Advancement of Science, the American Association of Applied Anthropology. He was a Diplomate in Clinical Psychology of the American Board of Psychological Hypnosis, of the Clinical Hypnosis of the American Board of Psychological Hypnosis, of the American Board of Medical Psychotherapists, and of the American Board of Sexology. Ellis has been President of the Advisory Council of Distinguished Humanists, has served as Vice-President of the American Academy of Psychotherapists, as Chairman of the Marriage Counseling Section of the National Council of Family Relations, and as Executive Committee Member of the Divisions of Psychotherapy and of Humanistic Psychology of the American Psychological Association, and of the New York Society of Clinical Psychologists.
Ellis has served as Consulting or Associate Editor of the following journals: • Journal of Marital and Family Therapy • The International Journal of Sexology • Existential Psychiatry • The Journal of Individual Psychology • The Journal of Contemporary Psychotherapy • Journal of Sex, Research • Voices: the Art and Science of Psychotherapy • Cognitive Therapy and Research • Psychological Reports • Journal of Rational-Emotive and Cognitive Behavior Therapy • Journal of Child and Adolescent Psychotherapy • Psychotherapy in Private Practice • Journal of Psychology and Human Sexuality • International Journal of Eclectic and Integrative Psychotherapy
Scope and Content
This collection consists of materials related to Albert Ellis's long career as a psychologist, sexologist, and pioneer of Rational Emotive Behavior Therapy (REBT). Records consist of correspondence, publications, photographs, notebooks, notecards, reel to reel audio tapes, audio cassette tapes, VHS tapes, and Dictaphone tapes.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in VI series
Series I. Correspondence, 1947-2006
Series II. Library and Research Files, 1931-2007
Series III. Notebooks, 1933-1963
Series IV. Notecards,Undated
Series V. Audio and Visual, 1953-2007
Subseries V.1: Audio Cassettes, 1966-2007
Subseries V.2: Reel to Reel Audio, 1953-1975
Subseries V.3: VHS, 1989-2003
Subseries V.3: Dictabelt, 1954-1965
Series VI. Photographs, 1920-2004
Subjects
American Academy of Psychotherapists.; American Association of Marriage Counselors.; American Psychological Association.; Barricade Books.; Carol Publishing.; Hawthorn Books.; Institute for Rational-Emotive Therapy (New York, N.Y.); Institute for Sex Research.; Science and Behavior Books.; Society for the Scientific Study of Sex (U.S.); Twayne Publishers.; Ard, Ben.; Barron, Jules.; Beck, Aaron T.; Branden, Barbara.; Branden, Nathaniel.; Ciardi, John.; Clark, Le Mon, 1897-; Corsini, Raymond J.; Crawford, Ted.; DiGiuseppe, Raymond.; Dryden, Windy.; Ellis, Albert, 1913-2007.; Ellis, Debbie Joffe, 1956-; Gebhard, Paul H.; Geis, H. Jon.; Gillette, Paul J.; Grieger, Russell.; Gullo, John M.; Guze, Henry.; Harper, Robert Allen.; Hauck, Paul.; Kinsey, Alfred C. (Alfred Charles), 1894-1956.; Lazarus, Arnold A.; Legman, Gershon, 1917-; Maultsby, Maxie C.; May, Rollo.; Meehl, Paul E. (Paul Everett), 1920-2003.; Montagu, Ashley, 1905-1999.; Pillay, A. P. (Alyappin Padmanabbha), 1890-; Pomeroy, Wardell Baxter.; Powers, Melvin, 1922-; Rand, Ayn.; Rogers, Carl R. (Carl Ransom), 1902-1987.; Sagarin, Edward, 1913-; Spectorsky, Auguste C., 1910-.; Stuart, Carol.; Stuart, Lyle.; Vernon, Ann.; Weinrach, Stephen G.; Wolfe, Janet L.; Behavior Therapy.; Blame.; Cognitive therapy.; Marital psychotherapy.; Marriage.; Marriage counseling.; Objectivism (Philosophy); Physician-Patient Relations.; Psychotherapy, Rational-Emotive.; Psychology.; Psychotherapy--methods.; Rational emotive behavior therapy.; Sexology--Research.; Journal of rational-emotive and cognitive-behavior therapy.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least two business days in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
Debbie Joffe Ellis Gift 2010
Albert Ellis Institute Gift 2010
- Series I: Correspondence, 1947-2006
  This series is arranged chronologically, with an index of names and organizations that appear on a frequent basis. Common themes found within this series consist of: editors from various publishers working with Ellis in regard to either his forthcoming books, or forthcoming books written by others. Ellis frequently collaborated on publications (books and journal articles) with other psychologists, as well as those not associated with the psychological field, with regard to RET practices and/or sexually related topics. Individuals contacting Ellis for advice, individuals with comment or questions regarding one of the books or articles he wrote, and individuals seeking information on REBT workshops figure prominently throughout all years encompassed. Much of the correspondence is from faculty of Psychology or Psychiatry departments at various universities. Many are from individuals requesting Ellis’s assistance in getting their book/article published. There are memoranda between individuals at the Albert Ellis Institute. Ellis’s itineraries and schedules, letters from various psychologists running RET institutes in other locales, both nationally and internationally, and requests for Ellis to speak at conferences, workshops, and symposia are consistent throughout this series. A variety of holiday, birthday, and get well cards can be found as well.
  - 1947-1955, (31 folders) (Box 118)
    (File Contains Materials Related To: Isley Boone, American Sunbathing Association (ASA); LeMon Clark; Hettie Ellis (photograph); Gladys Groves, National Council on Family Relations; Robert A. Harper, Merrill-Palmer School; Alfred C. Kinsey; Paul Meehl; Ashley Montagu; George Murdock; A.P. Pillay; Carl R. Rogers; Henry A. Ryan; Edward Sagarin (Pen Name: Donald Webster Cory); A.E. Smith, Values (Therapeutic and Otherwise) of Absolute Consistency; A.P. Spectorsky; Paul Wallin; Abstracts of Sexology; APA--Committee on Private Practice, Committee on Malpractice Insurance, Divisional Committee on Private Practice, Advisory Committee on Legislative Matters, Committee on Private Practice Annual Reports, Committee on Professional Liability Insurance; International Journal of Sexology; Journal of Criminal Law and Police Science; New York State Council of Psychologists on Legislation; New York State Psychiatric Institute; Sexology Magazine; Twayne Publishers, Inc., John Ciardi Editor for the American Sexual Tragedy and regarding The Psychology of Sex Offending)
  - 1955-1958, (32 folders) (Box 119)
    (File Contains Materials Related To: Nathaniel Branden; LeMon Clark; Raymond Corsini; Hettie Ellis; Paul Ellis; Robert A. Harper; Rollo May; Paul Meehl; Charles Odom; Wardell B. Pomeroy; Carl R. Rogers; Barney Rosset, Grove Press; Rhoda Winter Russell; Michael Seriven; Lyle Stuart; American Academy of Psychotherapists (AAP), First Annual Conference of, Panel What is Psychotherapy", Second Annual Conference; American Association of Marriage Counselors, Inc.; Contemporary Psychology; Encyclopedia of Sex; Encyclopedia of Sexual Behavior; The Moreno Institute; New York Society of Clinical Psychologists; Sex Without Guilt; Sexology Magazine; Society for the Scientific Study of Sex (SSSS))
  - 1960s (Box 119)
    (Notable Correspondents Include: Noble H. Kelley, Southern Illinois University; George Walsh, Editor, Cosmopolitan; Cec Cinder, Editor, Utopia Publications; Brian Kirby, Editor, Brandon House; Jerry DeVincent, Editor, Verdict; Martin Grossack, Grossack Research Associates; Seymore Krim, Nugget Magazine; Isadore Rubin, Editor, Sexology Magazine; John Warkentin, Journal Editor, Voices: The Art and Science of Psychotherapy ;The International Platform Association; Carnegie Institute of Technology; Fact Magazine; Psychology Club, College of San Mateo, California; Prentice-Hall, Inc.; Veterans Administration; Julian Messner, Inc. Publishers; The Realist; Janus Society of America; Journal of Marriage and Family; Charles C. Thomas Publisher; Dugald S. Arbuckle, Boston University; Grove Press; Aaron Beck; Herbert Michelman, Crown Publishers; Department of Health, Commonwealth of Pennsylvania; Paul G. Neimark, Editor, New Classics House; State of Georgia, Milledgeville State Hospital; A.C. Spectorsky, Editorial Director, Playboy; Robert A. Wilson, Editor, Country Wide Publications; The Language Press; A & W Publishers, Inc.; Impact Publishers; The Fielding Institute, California; Zift-Davis Publishing, Co.; American Association of Sex Educators, Counselors and Therapists, Washington, DC; Indiana School of Nursing; Springer Publishing; Russell Grieger, University of Virginia)
  - 1958-1963, (23 folders) (Box 120)
    (File Contains Materials Related To: LeMon Clark; Dolores Donnett (photograph); Hettie Ellis; Robert A. Harper; Robert Salomon; Lyle Stuart; Rhoda Winter Russell; Activities of the Institute of Rational Living; Advanced Training Seminar of the Institute for Rational Living; AAP; the Adams School; Encyclopedia of Sexual Behavior; Long John Program, Radio Station WOR; Psychological Reports; SSSS)
  - 1960-1961 (Box 97)
    (File Contains Materials Related To: The Art and Science of Love--Includes Notes)
  - 1963, (17 folders) (Box 121)
    (File Contains Materials Related To: Ben Ard; LeMon Clark; Raymond Corsini; Ted Crawford; Hettie Ellis; Paul Ellis; Ralph Ginzburg, Eros Magazine; Al Goldstein; Robert A. Harper; Henry Guze; Charles Odom; Barney Rosset, Grove Press; Rhoda Winter Russell; Lyle Stuart; John Wilcock, the Village Voice; AAP; American Association for Humanistic Psychology; APA, Hawthorn Books; International Council of Psychologists; New Era Club; Nugget Magazine; Nymphomania: A Study of the Over-Sexed Woman; Psychologists in Private Practice (PPP); The Realist; Sexology Magazine)
  - 1963-1965, (19 folders) (Box 122)
    (File Contains Materials Related To: Ben Ard; Nathaniel Branden; LeMon Clark; Raymond Corsini; Hettie Ellis; Paul H. Gebhard, Institute for Sex Research, Inc.; Robert A. Harper; Hugh Hefner; Wardell B. Pomeroy; Edward Sagarin (Pen Name: Donald Webster Cory); Carl R. Rogers; Rhoda Winter Russell; Lyle Stuart; American Journal of Psychotherapy; APA; CLYDE; Cosmopolitan; Crown Publishers; FACT Magazine; Grove Press; New Classics House Regarding Uncensored Essays on Sex and Psychotherapy, by Albert Ellis; Journal of Sex Research; Playboy; Project TACT (Technical Automated Compatibility Testing); Psychologists Interested in the Advancement of Psychotherapy; Sexology Magazine; Seymour Press; Voices: Journal of the American Academy of Psychotherapists)
  - 1965, (13 folders) (Box 123)
    (File Contains Materials Related To: Ben Ard; Aaron T. Beck; Hettie Ellis; Robert A. Harper; Hugh Hefner; Bertha Klausner; Edward Sagarin (Pen Name: Donald Webster Cory); Rhoda Winter Russell; Lyle Stuart; Janet Wolfe; Alfred Adler Institute; AAP; American Association of Marriage Counselors; APA; Brandon House; International Society for General Semantics; New Classics House; Playboy; Psychotherapy; Sexology Magazine; SSSS; Voices: Journal of the American Academy of Psychotherapists)
  - 1965, (7 folders) (Box 126)
    (File Contains Materials Related To: Hettie Ellis ;Lyle Stuart; Edward Sagarin (Pen Name: Donald Webster Cory); APA; Brandon House; Cosmopolitan; Country Wide Publications; Grove Press; Journal of Marriage and the Family; New Classics House; Playboy; Sexology Magazine; SSSS)
  - 1966, (6 folders) (Box 123)
    (File Contains Materials Related To: Barney Rosset, Grove Press; Edward Sagarin (Pen Name: Donald Webster Cory); Lyle Stuart; APA; Cosmopolitan; National Council on Crime and Delinquency; New York Institute of Existential Analysis, Inc.; Pageant; Playboy; SSSS)
  - 1966, (17 folders) (Box 124)
    (File Contains Materials Related To: Nathaniel Branden; Ted Crawford; Hettie Ellis; Paul Ellis; Robert A. Harper; Hugh Hefner; Myra Josephs; Rhoda Winter Russell; Edward Sagarin (Pen Name: Donald Webster Cory); Lyle Stuart; Janet Wolfe; American Association of State Psychology Boards; AAP; APA; Crown Publishers; Existential Psychiatry; Harvard Business Review; Holiday Cards; Journal of Consulting Psychology; The Journal of Nervous and Mental Disease; Playboy; Prentice-Hall, Inc.; Sexology Magazine; SSSS; Twayne Publishers; Voices: Journal of the American Academy of Psychotherapists)
  - 1966, (15 folders) (Box 125)
    (File Contains Materials Related To: Ted Crawford; Hettie Ellis; Robert A. Harper; Gershon Legman; Lyle Stuart; Edward Sagarin (Pen Name: Donald Webster Cory); Rhoda Winter Russell; AAP; APA; Cosmopolitan; Playboy; Voices: Journal of the American Academy of Psychotherapists)
  - 1966-1967, (18 folders) (Box 127)
    (File Contains Materials Related To: Barbara Branden; Nathaniel Branden Regarding Ellis and Ayn Rand; LeMon Clark; Henry Guze; Hugh Hefner; Paul E. Meehl; Rhoda Winter Russell; Lyle Stuart; Janet Wolfe; Esalen Institute; Playboy; Sexology Magazine)
  - 1967, (19 folders) (Box 128)
    (File Contains Materials Related To: Nathaniel Branden Regarding Ellis Debate with Ayn Rand; Gershon Bach; Charles Odom; Robert A. Harper; Gershon Legman; Melvin Powers; Rhoda Winter Russell; Richard L. Rhodes; Edward Sagarin (Pen Name: Donald Webster Cory); Lyle Stuart; Clyde H. Ward; APA; Columbia College Today; Esalen Institute; Gent; International Literary Agency; Playboy; Psychology Today; Christmas Cards; Hot Off the Griddle, by Anonymous)
  - 1968, (20 folders) (Box 129)
    (File Contains Materials Related To: Hettie Ellis; John M. Gullo; Henry Guze; Robert A. Harper; Lyle Stuart; Aldine Publishing Co.; Alfred Politz Research (APR); American Board of Examiners in Professional Psychology; APA, Program--Division 20; Journal of Pastoral Counseling; Macfadden-Bartell Corp Regarding Search for Sexual Enjoyment; Mattachine Society, Inc.; Playboy; Voices: Journal of the American Academy of Psychotherapists; Prentice-Hall, Inc.; New York State Psychiatric Institute; Sex Information and Education Council of Canada (SIECCAN); Sexology Magazine)
  - 1968, (19 folders) (Box 130)
    (File Contains Materials Related To: George R. Bach; Helen Gurley Brown, Cosmopolitan; LeMon Clark; Hettie Ellis; Robert A. Harper; Hugh Hefner; Al Goldstein, Screw Magazine; Myra Josephs; Charles Odom; K.M. Phadke; Rhoda Winter Russell; Edward Sagarin (Pen Name: Donald Webster Cory); Lyle Stuart; Aldine Publishing; APA; Dell Publications; Esalen Institute; Grove Press; Kairos; Journal of Sex Research; New York Magazine; Psychiatric Opinion; Psychology Today; Sociological Abstracts; SSSS; Voices: Journal of the American Academy of Psychotherapists)
  - 1968-1969, (15 folders) (Box 131)
    (File Contains Materials Related To: Ben Ard; George Bach; James Bard; Aaron T. Beck; Raymond Corsini; Paul H. Gebhard; Martin Grossack; Henry Guze; Robert A. Harper; Gershon Legman; Nelson Mallary; K. M. Phadke; Wardell B. Pomeroy; Rhoda Winter Russell; Edward Sagarin (Pen Name: Donald Webster Cory); Lyle Stuart; Ivan Veit, New York Times Regarding Censorship; Earl Wilson; Janet Wolfe; APA; Columbia Literary Society; Elysium; Journal of Sex Research; Playboy; Rational Training Institute, Winter-Spring, 1968 Sexology Magazine; SSSS; Sexpo '68--Oklahoma State University; Voices: Journal of the American Academy of Psychotherapists)
  - 1969, (16 folders) (Box 132)
    (File Contains Materials Related To: Ben Ard; Aaron T. Beck; Alan P. Bell; Gay Bryant, Raymond Corsini; Hettie Ellis; Paul Ellis; Paul Gebhard; Martin Grossack; John Gullo; Gershon Legman; Nelson Mallary; Edward Sagarin (Pen Name: Donald Webster Cory); Rhoda Winter Russell; Lyle Stuart; AAP; APA; Avant Garde; Center for Behavior Modification, Inc. (CBM); Elysium; International Journal of Psychiatry; Jack McKinney Show; Julian Press; Kairos; Mademoiselle; Mensa Journal; New York Society for General Semantics; Penthouse Magazine; Rene Guyon Society; Social Science Research Bureau; Playboy; Psychological Reports; Voices: Journal of the American Academy of Psychotherapists)
  - 1969, (16 folders) (Box 133)
    (File Contains Materials Related To: Ben Ard; Eileen Brand, Creative Services; LeMon Clark; Raymond Corsini; Hettie Ellis; Paul Gebhard; Al Goldstein; Martin Grossack; John Gullo; Robert A. Harper; Paul Hauck; Bertha Klausner; Nelson Mallary; Melvin Powers, Wilshire Book Company; Rhoda Winter Russell; Edward Sagarin (Pen Name: Donald Webster Cory); Lyle Stuart; AAP; APA--1969 Psychotherapy Research Conference; Elysium; Glamour; Guyon Society; Journal of Sex Research; Julian Press; Kairos; Life Extension Institute; Playboy; Psychology Today; Richard Fulton, Inc.; SSSS; Sexual Freedom League)
  - 1969 (Box 75)
    (File Contains Materials Related To: Ellis’s Macy’s Account)
  - 1970s (Notable Correspondents Include: Federal Correctional Institution, California; Paul Dawson, Dawson Feature Films Corp; University of Pennsylvania, Department of Psychiatry; University of Northern Colorado, Greeley, Colorado; Edwin Wagner, University of Akron, Ohio; American Association of Sex Educators, Counselors, and Therapists (AASECT), D.C.; Readers Digest Press, Suzanne Howard, Editor; Roger Libby, State University of New York at Albany, Department of Sociology; Gerald Rosen, University of Oregon, Psychology Department; American Society of Psychologists in Private Practice, Samuel Kutash, Program Chair; Paul Ellis; Clayton Shorkey, University of Texas at Austin, School of Social Work; Griffin Clinic, Encino, California; Barry Singer, California State University, Long Beach; E.J. Schmitt, Psychotherapist, Institute for Medical, Psychological Education and Therapy, Department of Health Training School, Dusseldorf, Germany; Center for Dynamic Therapy (CDI), Los Alamitos, California; Stephen Weinrach, Villanova University) (Box 75)
  - 1970, (18 folders) (Box 134)
    (File Contains Materials Related To: Hettie Ellis; Paul Ellis; Paul Gebhard; Martin Grossack; Robert A. Harper; Paul Hauck; Myra Josephs; Rhoda Winter Russell; Edward Sagarin (Pen Name: Donald Webster Cory); Lyle Stuart; Janet Wolfe; APA; Association for Humanistic Psychology; Journal of Sex Research; Mensa Journal; Penthouse; Playboy; Psychological Reports; Psychology Today; Richard Fulton, Inc.; Sexual Behavior; Voices: Journal of the American Academy of Psychotherapists)
  - 1970, (16 folders) (Box 135)
    (File Contains Materials Related To: Ben Ard; George R. Bach; Jules Barron; LeMon Clark; Ted Crawford; Paul Ellis; Paul Gebhard; Paul Gillette; Bertha Klausner; Martin Grossack; John Gullo; Robert A. Harper; Paul Hauck; Arnold Lazarus; Melvin Power; Jefferson Fuck Poland; Rhoda Winter Russell; Lyle Stuart; Janet Wolfe; APA; American Humanist Association; American Society of Alderian Psychology; Columbia Literary Society; Elysium; The Humanist; International Society for General Semantics; Julian Press, Inc; Proposed Ellis Report for Penthouse International; SSSS; Science and Behavior Books, Inc.; WABC-TV)
  - 1970-1971, (11 folders) (Box 136)
    (File Contains Materials Related To: Ben Ard; George R. Bach; Milton Blum; Raymond Corsini; Ted Crawford; Hettie Ellis; Paul Ellis; Jefferson Fuck; Paul Gillette; Al Goldstein; Martin Grossack; Robert A. Harper; Paul Hauck; Myra Josephs; Arnold Lazarus; Gershon Legman; Edward Sagarin (Pen Name: Donald Webster Cory); Artie Shaw; Lyle Stuart; Rhoda Winter Russell; Janet Wolfe; APA; Association for Advancement of Behavior Therapy; Esalen Institute; The Humanist; Penthouse; Playboy; Science and Behavior Books; Society of Separationists; SSSS; SIECCAN; Women's Wear Daily; WCBS-TV)
  - 1971, (13 folders) (Box 137)
    (File Contains Materials Related To: Aaron T. Beck; Raymond Corsini; Ted Crawford; Rebecca Dixon, Institute for Sex Research; John Gullo; Arnold Lazarus; Henry Guze; Martin Grossack; Paul Hauck; Nicholas Hobbs, The American Psychological Foundation, Inc.; Melvin Powers; Edward Sagarin (Pen Name: Donald Webster Cory); Lyle Stuart; Janet Wolfe; American Humanist Association; Forum: the International Journal of Human Relations; Dick Cavatt Show; First Annual New York Erotic Film Festival; Freundin; Grove Press; Hart Publishing Co., Inc.; Julian Press; Oasis; Parade Publications, Inc.; Peter Wyden, Inc.; Penthouse; Playboy; Science and Behavior Books; Sexual Behavior; WABC-TV--A.M. New York)
  - 1971-1972, (13 folders) (Box 138)